THE INNOCENTS
Henriette , did you bring any tools ?
- What did you say ? - Did you bring up any tools ?
No .
I think they 're down in the car .
Remember , all this is twice as new to her .
But Dad can stay with Anna . You and I can go on holiday together .
And I get to pick a magazine at the airport .
That sounds nice , but Daddy has a new job . Taking time off so soon would look weird .
And I have so much to do here . But this will be great .
You will meet lots of kids from your new school , and make new friends .
- But everybody 's away on summer holiday . - No , they 're not . Go to sleep , now .
- Good night . - I 'm not going to sleep .
All right , that 's fine by me .
Can you stay for a little while ?
No , I can 't . But I can leave the door open .
There ! Now I can hear you . Good night .
Hi .
- Are you new here ? - Yes .
Want to see something ?
What ?
Back where I used to live , I had a treehouse that I built all by myself .
I had a slingshot there .
I fired it at people I didn 't like . At people I think are mean .
- Have you moved ? - Yes . Many times .
Hold this , and stand right there .
- Should I toss it ? - No , just drop it in front of me .
- Are you ready ? - Yes .
Now !
Let 's find a lighter one .
- Ready ? - Yes .
Now .
Wow !
How did you do that ?
- I 've been practicing a lot . - Do it again .
Are you ready ?
Now .
- May I try ? - Yup .
You need to focus hard , okay ?
Now .
That didn 't work .
Watch this .
Wow !
Ew ! That 's just weird .
Can you move this ?
Nope !
But I can !
It swerved , sort of .
Did he use a slingshot ?
No .
He just sort of made it happen .
Be careful around slingshots .
- He knows magic ? - Yes .
- Neat . - What 's wrong ?
There were also some kids playing football .
That 's good !
They wouldn 't let me play , though .
They 'd probably just divided into teams .
I 'll do it .
I 'll take the pillow .
Look at that . A chair .
Look . Chair .
Come over here .
There !
Dad is waiting for us , we have to go . Always in a hurry ...
Yes , so do you .
I think my hair is a bit thicker than yours .
Mine is much darker .
Let me show you . This is your color , and this is mine .
Mine is darker than yours . Like that .
What a mean thing to say .
Nobody has nicer hair than anyone else .
Sorry , but you mustn 't fidget so much while I 'm brushing .
Mommy ?
Ow !
I 'm a trained nurse . I worked as a nurse before this .
So I know a good place when I see it .
She never speaks ? No expressive language ?
She makes certain sounds , but ... No .
She used to be able to speak ...
She was diagnosed at the age of four ?
Yes , but it started earlier .
She knew a lot of words , but lost them quite fast .
She wasn 't just echoing your words ?
No , she had the language of an ordinary 3-year-old .
Maybe I should show you around , Anna ?
Do you like to play ?
Oh my !
So much blood ! Hey ...
Hey , you ...
Anna ?
- What has happened ? - There 's broken glass here .
Susu !
KEEP DOOR CLOSED
Susu ?
- Could you take Anna out for a while ? - No .
- Just down to the playground . - No . I don 't want to .
- Good night . - Night night .
- Mom ? - Yes ?
When I pray , can I say something else if I want to ?
Yes , you can . Yes , you can do it the way you like .
You can pray for Daddy too , if you want .
- Can I just listen ? - What do you mean ?
Just listen ?
Yes ... But that 's not the same as praying .
- I think so . - Okay .
- Good night . Sleep , now . - Night night .
We 're going many places . We 're going to town as well .
With all my friends and my brother 's friends .
You can 't say stuff like that .
That 's a rotten thing to do .
I have to tell someone .
Is that your sister ?
She 's autistic .
Stop it .
Watch this .
Can 't she see ?
Yes , she 's just a little weird .
Are you pinching her hard ?
Yes .
Want to play ?
Sit here for a bit .
We won 't be long .
She can sit like that for ages .
Hey . What 's up ?
Want the ball ?
Well , do you ?
Hi .
Jabba !
- Is it yours ? - No . It was here yesterday .
I named it " Jabba " .
Hi , Jabba .
- Even higher up ? - Yes !
Jabba ...
Do you think it 's dead ?
Should we kill it ?
What do you mean ?
Don 't !
Did you hear that ?
It 's warm .
- Where are you going ? - I have to go home .
Anna , come . We have to go .
Come !
She wants to stay .
But we have to go ! Come !
Do you want to walk together ?
Could you take her out tomorrow ?
I 'm not sure .
- Come . - She wants to .
I can ask .
Can I take Anna outside again today ?
- You want to ? - Mm .
Did that make you happy ?
Can we ?
Yes , just don 't go far , right ?
Is your phone charged ?
Yes .
How many ?
Five ?
One castle .
Two .
Three . Four .
Anna ?
Hi .
We have to go .
- Is that you ? - No , her .
That won 't work .
It 's way too big .
Just try . It will work .
Stand beside them . I think it works better together .
Ready ?
Anna couldn 't do it at home . She can only do it when she 's with you .
What are you guys up to ?
Can you do it too ?
No .
Only me and her , then ?
- But you hear Anna , right ? - Yes .
- And she can hear me too . - Can you hear me ?
No . But him , a little .
What do you hear ?
Just something , you know .
But with her , I feel it all the time .
We think the same things . We think it together .
- Ready ? - Yes !
Banana .
- Banana ? - That 's right !
- You couldn 't hear us ? - No .
- Can you do that with Anna too ? - I can try .
- Ready ? - Yes .
Nope .
" Banana banana " .
- What 's that supposed to mean ? - Two bananas .
Try again . And you won 't say anything .
- Are you ready ? - Yes .
" Banano " !
Correct !
I cheated . I used her . It 's much easier with her .
I can 't do anything !
Let 's try with you two upstairs , and the two of us all the way down .
Hi .
All right , we 're on our way .
Bye .
We forgot about dinner . We have to go home now .
- Bye . - Bye .
- Hi ! Did everything go well ? - Yes .
- What 's for dessert ? - Ice cream !
Mom ?
Shark !
Mommy , may I watch TV ?
Okay ...
That one 's bigger .
Who are you talking to ?
No one . I 'm talking to someone who isn 't here .
Okay .
Answer me .
Hello .
Hello !
Benjamin , answer me when I 'm talking to you .
Answer me !
What are you doing ?
What is this mess ?
Aisha ?
Aisha !
Hey ?
Hey ! Are you OK ?
There was someone in my room .
It was probably just the TV . Come , let 's go to bed .
I 'll sit with you for a while .
Fart !
Try going even further that way !
Down there !
" Ben is a turd . "
Ben is a turd !
It 's not okay to laugh at others !
She laughed at me !
No !
Are you sure ?
Ow .
It hurts !
Stop it !
Go away !
- Go away . - Jerk .
She can 't feel anything .
Yes , she does .
Then why isn 't she crying ? She never cries .
She cries on the inside .
Yes , you can .
Just say it out loud , like I do .
Yes , you can do it .
No ...
You 're doing it !
You said it !
You said it just now !
Hi .
Does it hurt a lot ?
It ...
It 's biting me .
- Mom ? - Hello .
Did something happen ?
She fell .
Are you OK ? Hey you ...
Let 's take off your shoes .
Oh my God !
That must hurt so much !
What have you been up to ?
- We were walking , and she fell . - On the playground ?
Don 't lie to me . I can see that this was no fall .
What happened ? Tell me .
I 'm talking to you ! What happened ?
Can 't I trust you at all ?
- She 's fine . - No , she isn 't .
She is quite clearly not fine .
Come , dear . Mommy will fix it .
You 'll be fine .
Come in .
Hi .
Sorry for being so hard on you .
It 's not your responsibility to look after Anna .
It 's great that you want to try .
But it 's too big a responsibility .
So this is all on me .
What are you up to , when you stay out for so long ?
This and that . I don 't always remember .
What happened today , then ?
You weren 't actually on the playground , were you ?
I won 't get angry . I know you did your best .
I 'd just really like to know what happened .
Mommy ?
- Anna is much better . - Is she ?
She plays , and she can say things , in a way .
She can speak .
It 's true .
- This isn 't funny . Don 't joke about it . - I 'm not !
Just stop it .
Anna ?
Say something .
That 's enough , Ida .
Who 's that ? Can you tell me who that is ?
" Mommy " .
Mo ...
Ida ...
Come on , you just did it !
- Say it ! - Stop it .
- Say it ! - Didn 't you hear me ? Stop !
I will give you one more chance to tell me how Anna hurt herself .
No ?
Then I can no longer trust you with Anna .
You get that , right ?
I don 't care !
Ow ! Fuck !
You 're laughing at me ?
Any idea how much this hurts ?
What the fuck is wrong ...
Aisha and I are just fine .
But I 'm tired . I work night and day .
Yes .
- Mommy ? - What ?
Mommy ...
You 're bleeding .
- You 're bleeding . - What ?
You 're bleeding here .
- Stop it . - Your forehead is bleeding !
I 'm not bleeding , Aisha . Stop that nonsense .
It 's my daughter Aisha .
Now I can hear you .
I heard about that .
Mommy ...
Benjamin ! You must call someone ...
Call an ...
Hi ?
Anna ?
We 'll tidy up .
We 'll tidy up . We 're just playing .
Mm , we 're just playing .
We will tidy up , Mommy . We will .
Are you OK ?
What 's wrong ?
I 'm OK .
What 's it called ?
What 's its name ?
What 's it called ? It goes " toot toot " .
- Henriette ... - Give her some time . She 's tired .
She doesn 't like it .
What could this be ?
Can you tell me what it is ? It 's what I drink out of .
Glass .
Did you hear that ?
Did you hear that ? Who 's this ?
Who 's this ?
Can you say it ?
" Daddy " .
What did you say ?
Daddy .
- Well done ! - That was great !
Poor boy .
It 's terrible . Poor parents .
Do you think Ida knew him ?
- Do you think Ida had met him ? - No , no . She 's nine . He was ...
Yeah , he was older . 14 , it says here . Just awful .
- Aisha ? - Yes ?
- I 'd like you to stay home today . - Why ?
Because I say so .
- Don 't go far today . - OK .
You never go out on the footbridge , do you ?
No , no .
- Bye . - Bye .
What is it ?
Are you OK ?
I ... can
" fetch " people .
What do you mean ?
I can make people do things .
What things ?
Things I want them to do .
Yeah , right .
- But it 's true ! - Do it on me , then .
No .
Yes .
Come on !
You 're just kidding .
Don 't look .
Why not ?
And promise not to laugh .
- How did you do that ? - I don 't know .
This was a snake .
What ?
Didn 't you do that ?
No , that must 've been you .
I just wanted to get you onto the fridge .
- Are you afraid of snakes ? - Yes , very .
Hold it high .
- Like this ? - A bit further from your face .
Wow !
You 'd much rather be like that !
When you look like that , Anna , what are you ?
- Happy . - Yes , then you 're happy !
Then you smile and fool around .
You can smile with your teeth , or like this . Some people do that .
Just smile like this .
They 're running so fast ...
What are you up to ?
Wait and see .
Aisha ?
Stop ! What are you doing ? !
Stay out of it !
Mommy ...
My God ...
You mustn 't run away like that ! Where have you been ?
- Outside . - Outside ?
You can 't just go out , silly .
You know you can 't go out alone , right ? So great that you found her !
What is it ?
We must stop him . He
is out to get us .
He will hurt us .
He makes others do it .
But what are you ...
What are you planning ?
You don 't have to help us .
We can take care of it .
Together .
The boy who died ...
Ben did that .
But you already know that .
- Mommy , can I bring Anna outside ? - No .
- I 'll look after her . I promise . - No , don 't you know what time it is ?
Just for a little bit . It 's important !
Tomorrow we can go outside and play all day .
It 's suppertime . Who 'd like some ?
- Mommy ? - Yes ?
May I sleep in your room tonight ?
- Are you scared ? - Yes .
Come , now .
- Good night . - Good night .
- Mommy ? - Yes ?
- Are you working tonight ? - No , not tonight .
- When will you go to bed ? - Quite soon .
Try to get some sleep , now .
Mommy ?
- Yes ? - Can you get Boffa for me ?
- Where is it ? - In my bed .
OK . I 'll find him for you .
Anna ?
Mommy ?
Don 't be like that !
Stop it , Mommy !
Aisha ?
Aisha !
- Mommy ? - Yes ...
You 'll be fine . You 'll be fine !
She 's bleeding a lot ! Come quick !
Our address is Odvar Solbergs Plass 85 . Come quick !
Aisha .
- Can I have a band aid ? - Yes , you can .
Aisha , they 're on their way ! Please !
Aisha !
Aisha , you must wake up .
Wake up ! Aisha , please ...
Hi .
You knew her a little , didn 't you ?
Yes .
Oh dear . That was horrible .
But ...
You or Mommy could never do anything like that , right ?
No !
Ida , baby girl ... No !
Don 't you ever think like that .
Of course not ! We would never harm you .
Her mommy was sick . Sick in the mind .
She was all alone , and ...
It 's completely different . We 'd never do something like that to you .
You know that , right ?
Yes .
Come , now .
Anna , are you coming ?
What the ...
Let 's go .
Please ! I can 't do anything !
Please wake up !
He 's going to get us !
Please !
I 'm sorry .
- Mommy ? - Yes ?
What do you do when someone 's mean ?
Has someone been mean to you ?
No , no .
But what if someone is mean ?
Or going to do something mean ?
Then you tell it to a grown-up .
What if you are a grown-up ?
Then you may have to take care of it on your own .
Or go to the police , if they can help .
Are you sure no one is being mean to you ?
No .
Okay . Sleep tight .
Sleep tight .
- I 'll go outside . - OK .
- Mommy ? - Yes ?
Oh dear .
Are you OK ?
Hey ...
Bye .
Bye ...
Who is it ?
It 's Ida .
Wait there , I 'll come down .
Hi .
Do you want to do something ?
Where 's your sister ?
She 's at home . She 's not doing that well .
What do you have there ?
- Come on ! - Where are we going ?
We need some altitude !
- Want to throw it ? - Okay !
It 'll get destroyed !
Here you go .
It 's better over here .
Shit , it 's going to hit a car !
- Are you ready ? - Yes .
Hey ! Get down from there !
Get down !
Hey , stop !
Hey , you !
Come back !
Hey !
Ow !
Hey ...
Hey , it 's Mommy . You 're in the hospital .
How are you ?
Yes .
They say you have a concussion .
So if you can 't remember everything , that 's completely normal .
What happened to the boy ?
He 's fine .
Apparently , he got up and ran away .
Is he a friend of yours ?
Ida ...
Who is he ?
Ida ?
I don 't know .
That 's odd , because someone said it looked like you ...
That you pushed him over on purpose .
What really happened ?
We were just playing .
OK .
That 's OK .
There ! I 'll take those .
- Are you OK ? - Yes .
People are coming home from vacation .
What was that ?
Nothing .
Ida ?
I forgot to buy something . Can you stay here with Anna for a bit ?
Yes , that 's fine .
Bye !
Mommy ?
Anna ?
Anna !
Hello , girls .
There 's an ambulance outside . You may see it from the balcony .
Everything went well ?
What happened to your cast ?
Oh !
Oh dear .
Mommy ...
There , there .
There , there , little one .